Guide to the Brand Blanshard Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writing, 1913-1989; Series II; 6.5 linear feet (16 boxes)
  - Manuscripts
    - "Puritanism," delivered at various locations, 1936-1945 (Box 37, Folder 57)
    - Jesse Holmes testimonial dinner, 1937 January 5 (Box 37, Folder 58)
    - On the psychological roots of war, Perdie Hill, 1937 October 26 (Box 37, Folder 59)
    - "Metaphysics and Social Attitudes," Social Frontier, Circa 1937 December (Box 37, Folder 60)
    - "Philosophy, War, and Peace," delivered at various locations, 1937 (Box 37, Folder 61)
    - "Standards," delivered at various locations, 1937-1942 (Box 37, Folder 62)
    - "Education," delivered at various locations, 1937-1944 (Box 37, Folder 63)
    - On Quakerism, delivered at various locations, 1937-1946 (Box 37, Folder 64)
    - Untitled, Student conference, Swarthmore, 1938 March 19 (Box 37, Folder 65)
    - "Silence," Swarthmore First Day School, 1938 May 15 (Box 37, Folder 66)
    - "Discussion of Dr. Mercier's Paper," Proceedings of the American Catholic Philosophical Association, 1938 (Box 37, Folder 67)
    - "The Future and Patriotism," delivered at various locations, 1938 (Box 37, Folder 68)
    - On Quaker preaching, delivered at various locations, 1938-1939 (Box 37, Folder 69)
    - "The Spirit of France", 1939 October 11 (Box 37, Folder 70)
    - "Watcher, What of the Night?", 1939 (Box 37, Folder 71)
    - "The Place of Anger in the Good Life," delivered at various locations, 1939-1940 (Box 37, Folder 72)
    - "The Situation in Europe - Background and Impressions," delivered at various locations, 1939-1940 (Box 37, Folder 73)
    - "Why I Am Not a Pacifist," The Friend, Circa 1940 May 2 (Box 37, Folder 74)
    - Comments at Mrs. Thatcher's funeral, Swarthmore, 1940 June 11 (Box 37, Folder 75)
    - "John W. Nason", 1940 October 25 (Box 37, Folder 76)
    - "Pacifism - Right and War," delivered at various locations, 1940-1944 (Box 37, Folder 77)
    - "Pacifism, Right and Wrong," Hollins College, 1941 February 21 (Box 37, Folder 78)
    - "The Nature of Mind," Journal of Philosophy, Circa 1941 April 10 (Box 37, Folder 79)
    - "Intervention," Summit Presbyterian Church, 1941 November 9 (Box 37, Folder 80)
    - "Premises of Peace," Swarthmore College, 1941 November 16 (Box 37, Folder 81)
    - "Religion: Marks of the Religious Mind," delivered at various locations, 1941 (Box 37, Folder 82)
    - "Sincerity," delivered at various locations, 1941-1945 (Box 37, Folder 83)
    - Jesse Holmes Memorial Service, Friends Meeting House, Swarthmore, 1942 May 31 (Box 37, Folder 84)
    - On reconstruction, International Relations Club, Swarthmore, 1942 July 12 (Box 37, Folder 85)
    - "The Ethics of Belief," First Day School Adult Class, 1942 October 25 (Box 37, Folder 86)
    - On philosophy, 1942 October (Box 37, Folder 87)
    - "Fact, Value, and Science," delivered at various locations, 1942 (Box 37, Folder 88)
    - "Critique of Richard Brandt," delivered to colleagues and G. E. Moore at Swarthmore, Circa 1942-1944 (Box 37, Folder 89)
    - On reconstruction, Mrs. Cookston's study group, Rose Valley, 1943 April 14 (Box 37, Folder 90)
    - "The Divided Mind," delivered at various locations, 1943-1944 (Box 37, Folder 91)
    - "Silence: A Children's Sermon," George School, 1944 May 14 (Box 37, Folder 92)
    - "The Gift of Quakerism," radio speech (WDAS), Swarthmore, 1944 October 28 (Box 37, Folder 93)
    - "The Great Commandment," Society of Friends General Conference, 1944 (Box 37, Folder 94)
    - "Thought Without Tears" ("Workshop of the Unconscious"), American Mercury, Circa 1945 December (Box 37, Folder 95)
    - "On Understanding Americans," delivered at various locations, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 96)
    - "Reason in Philosophy and in Life," Vassar College, 1946 April 3 (Box 37, Folder 97)
    - Memorial Day address, 1946 May (Box 37, Folder 98)
    - "Education an Unfinished Business," Friends Seminary New York, 1946 June 6 (Box 37, Folder 99)
    - "The Nature of Man", 1946 December (Box 37, Folder 100)
    - Articles for Collier's Encyclopedia, Circa 1946-1948 (Box 38, Folder 101)
    - "Christmas," Calhoun College, 1948 December 15 (Box 38, Folder 102)
    - "Limited Minds and Unlimited Knowledge," delivered at various locations, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 103)
    - Noble Lectures. Harvard Divinity School, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 104)
    - On Northrop's view of ethical judgement, Graduate Club, 1949 February 25 (Box 38, Folder 105)
    - Debate with T. M. Greene, 1949 March 13 (Box 38, Folder 106)
    - "Philosophy Teaching - Past and Present," Cleveland Conference on the teaching of philosophy, 1949 October (Box 38, Folder 107)
    - "The British Scholar - A Toast," British Academy, 1952 (Box 38, Folder 108)
    - "John Dewey", [1952] (Box 38, Folder 108a)
    - Untitled, Graduate Club, Yale, 1953 September 24 (Box 38, Folder 109)
    - Untitled, Social Science Club, 1953 October 26 (Box 38, Folder 110)
    - Notes for Salzburg Seminar on American Studies, 1953 (Box 38, Folder 111)
    - "Philosophical Style," delivered at various locations, 1953-1954 (Box 38, Folder 112)
    - "The Sources of Serenity," delivered at various locations, 1954 (Box 38, Folder 113)
    - "Scholar and Gentleman," delivered at various locations, 1954-1957 (Box 38, Folder 114)
    - "The Rational Temper," "The Reasonable Temper," delivered at various locations, 1954-1964 (Box 38, Folder 115)
    - "The Philosopher's Quest," Allegheny College, 1955 March 10 (Box 38, Folder 116)
    - "Reason in Conduct," Allegheny College, 1955 March 11 (Box 38, Folder 117)
    - "What Should We Get from College?," Randolph-Macon Women's College, 1955 September 26 (Box 38, Folder 118)
    - "Proof in Psychical Research," delivered at various locations, 1955-1957 (Box 38, Folder 119)
    - "Reason and Ethics," Wesleyan University, 1957 March 27 (Box 38, Folder 120)
    - "America's Cultural Resources for Leadership," Temple University, 1957 April 6 (Box 38, Folder 121)
    - "Frank Aydelotte," American Oxonian, Circa 1957 April (Box 38, Folder 122)
    - "Dewey in Retrospect," University of Vermont, 1957 October 17 (Box 38, Folder 123)
    - Discussion of Professor Turbane's paper on Berkeley, Philosophical Association, Boston, 1957 (Box 38, Folder 124)
    - "The Uses of Philosophy", Circa 1957 (Box 38, Folder 125)
    - "Discussion of President Hocking's Address," Metaphysical Society, 1958 March (Box 38, Folder 126)
    - Remarks at Arthur Pap's funeral, 1959 September 8 (Box 38, Folder 127)
    - "Body, Mind, and Science," Yale Scientific Magazine, Circa (Box 38, Folder 128)
    - "Symbolism," N.V. University symposium, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 129)
    - "The Reasonable Life," Earlham College, 1961 April 27 (Box 38, Folder 130)
    - "The Beginnings of Philosophy," Wesleyan University, Allegheny College, 1961 September (Box 38, Folder 131)
    - "Plato's Theory of Ideas," Wesleyan University, 1961 October 23 (Box 38, Folder 132)
    - Articles for the Grolier Encyclopedia, Circa 1961 (Box 38, Folder 133)
    - "The Philosophic Enterprise," Powell Lecture, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 134)
    - "Necessities in Nature," delivered at various locations, 1961-1962 (Box 39, Folder 135)
    - "On Being at the Center," Wesleyan University, [ca. 1961-1962] (Box 39, Folder 136)
    - Conformity lectures, delivered at various locations, 1961-1967 (Box 39, Folder 137)
    - "The Present Situation in Philosophy," delivered at various locations, 1961-1967 (Box 39, Folder 138)
    - "Practical Reason," "Reason and Feeling in 20th Century Ethics," and "Reason and Feeling in Present Day Ethics," delivered at various locations, 1961-1969 (Box 39, Folder 139)
    - "On Sanity in Thought and Art," University of Arizona and other locations, 1962 February (Box 39, Folder 140)
    - Foreword to An Introduction to the Philosophy of Science, Circa 1962 (Box 39, Folder 141)
    - "Rationalism: Descartes and Spinoza," delivered at various locations, 1962-1964 (Box 39, Folder 142)
    - "The Test of a University," delivered at various locations, 1962-1964 (Box 39, Folder 143)
    - "Science and the Humanities: A Balance Sheet," "Plea for the Humanities," "Why the Humanities," and other lectures on the humanities and science in education delivered at various locations, 1962-1967 (Box 39, Folder 144)
    - "Pope John and Reunion," Friends Journal, Circa 1963 May 15 (Box 39, Folder 145)
    - "The Specialist and the Humanist," Brown University, 1963 June 3 (Box 39, Folder 146)
    - "Naturalism and Human Nature," delivered at various locations, 1963 (Box 39, Folder 147)
    - "The Life of the Spirit in a Machine Age," delivered at various locations, 1963-1969 (Box 39, Folder 148)
    - "Life as Art," delivered at various locations, 1964 February (Box 39, Folder 149)
    - "Currents in American Thought" ("Les Courants de la Pensée Américaine") Les Études Philosophiques, Circa 1964 April-June (Box 39, Folder 150)
    - "Internal Relations," University of Indiana, 1964 October (Box 39, Folder 151)
    - "Some Comments on Economic Determinism," Society for the Philosophical Study of Dialectical Materialism, Boston (later published as "Reflections on Economic Determinism," Journal of Philosophy, 1964 December (Box 39, Folder 152)
    - "Philosophical Interrogations", 1964 (Box 39, Folder 153)
    - "The Fringe Benefits of Education," delivered at various locations, 1964-1965 (Box 39, Folder 154)
    - "Body and Mind," delivered at various locations, 1964-1967 (Box 39, Folder 155)
    - "Determinism," delivered at various locations, 1964-1973 (Box 40, Folder 156)
    - "Rationalism," delivered at various locations, 1964-1976 (Box 40, Folder 157)
    - "Wisdom," Encyclopedia of Philosophy, [ca. 1965 Jan] (Box 40, Folder 158)
    - "Critical Reflections on Behaviorism," proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, 1965 February 18 (Box 40, Folder 159)
    - "The Uses of Admiration," Mount Holyoke, 1965 June 6 (Box 40, Folder 160)
    - "The Fringe Benefits of Education," Lake Erie College, 1965 June 14
      See: box 79
    - "Eliot in Memory," Yale Review, Circa 1965 Summer (Box 40, Folder 161)
    - "The Rationalist in Politics," delivered at various locations, 1965-1967 (Box 40, Folder 162)
    - "Faith and Reason I - The Catholic Position," Wheaton College, 1966 April (Box 40, Folder 163)
    - "Faith and Reason II - The Protestant Tradition," Wheaton College, 1966 April (Box 40, Folder 164)
    - "Faith and Reason III - The View of a Liberal," delivered at various locations, 1966 April-1969 (Box 40, Folder 165)
    - "Reason and Unreason in Religion," Zygon, Circa 1966 June (Box 40, Folder 166)
    - "Retribution Revisited," University of Buffalo and other locations, 1966 October (Box 40, Folder 167)
    - On Kierkegaard, Personalist Discussion Group, Eastern Division Meeting of Philosophical Association, 1966 December 27 (Box 40, Folder 168)
    - "Kierkegaard on Religious Knowledge," Personalist Discussion Group, 1966 December (Box 40, Folder 169)
    - Foreword to New Studies in Berkeley's Philosophy, Circa 1966 (Box 40, Folder 170)
    - Foreword to Semantics and Necessary Truth, Circa 1966 (Box 40, Folder 171)
    - "In Defense of Metaphysics," Metaphysics: Readings and Reappraisals, Circa 1966 (Box 40, Folder 172)
    - "Significance," lectures given at the College of Wooster, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 173)
    - "William Ernest Hocking," Yearbook of American Philosophical Society, Circa 1966 (Box 40, Folder 174)
    - "Hocking as a Speculative Philosopher," Memorial Meeting, Harvard University, 1967 February 10 (Box 40, Folder 175)
    - "Internal Relations and Their Importance to Philosophy," Northampton Symposium on Internal Relations, 1967 May (Box 41, Folder 176)
    - "Rejoinder to My Critics," Smith Symposium, 1967 July (Box 41, Folder 177)
    - "The Liberal in Religion," syracuse University (also published in Religious Humanism, 1967 November 3 (Box 41, Folder 178)
    - "The Blessing of Libraries," Friends Historical Library, Swarthmore, 1967 December 8 (Box 41, Folder 179)
    - "The Great Grey Virtue" or "The Difficulties of Being Reasonable," delivered at various locations, 1967-1976 (Box 41, Folder 180)
    - "The Objectivity of Moral Judgement," delivered at various locations, 1967-1976 (Box 41, Folder 181)
    - "Reflections in a Library," Friends Journal, Circa 1968 March 15 (Box 41, Folder 182)
    - "The Limits of Naturalism", 1968 March (Box 41, Folder 183)
    - "The Liberal in Religion," The Humanist, Circa 1968 May-June (Box 41, Folder 184)
    - "Rejoinder to Mr. Kearns," Philosophy and Phenomenological Research, Circa 1968 September (Box 41, Folder 185)
    - "Frank Laurence Lucas," Yale Review, Circa 1968 Winter (Box 41, Folder 186)
    - "Bertrand Russell in Retrospect," delivered at various locations (also published in Dialogue ), 1968-1969 (Box 41, Folder 187)
    - "Lady Wylie in Memory," American Oxonian, Circa 1969 October (Box 41, Folder 188)
    - "Truth," American Philosophical Association, 1969 December 28 (Box 41, Folder 189)
    - Articles for The Penguin Companion to American Literature, [ca. 1969] (Box 41, Folder 190)
    - "Curt John Ducasse," Journal of American Society for Psychical Research, Circa 1970 April (Box 41, Folder 191)
    - "Rejoinder to Mr. Oakes," The Personalist, Circa 1970 Spring (Box 41, Folder 192)
    - "Some Memories of the Social Science Club on Its Centennial", 1970 October 26 (Box 41, Folder 193)
    - "The Revolt Against Reason in Theology," American Philosophical Society, 1970 November 12 (Box 41, Folder 194)
    - "The Ethics of Belief," delivered at various locations (also published in Philosophic Exchange, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 195)
    - "Rationalism," Encyclopedia Britannica, Circa 1971 (Box 41, Folder 196)
    - "Beyond Dignity," Yale Conference on the work of B. F. Skinner, 1972 April 19 (Box 41, Folder 197)
    - "Catholicism and Humanism," La Farge Center, New York, 1972 May (Box 41, Folder 198)
    - "Democracy and Distinction in American Education," University of Utah, 1973 November 9 (Box 41, Folder 199)
    - "Toast," Philosophical Association, 1973 December 22 (Box 41, Folder 200)
    - "Humanist Reply," for The Humanist, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 201)
    - "A Reply to My Critics," Idealistic Studies, Circa 1974 May (Box 41, Folder 202)
    - "Sidgwick the Man,", Circa 1974 July (Box 41, Folder 203)
    - "Rationalism in Ethics and Religion," Mid-Twentieth Century American Philosophy, Circa 1974 (Box 41, Folder 204)
    - "The Uses of a Liberal Education," delivered at various locations, 1974 (Box 41, Folder 205)
    - "On Being Emeritus" ("For One Who is Liberally Educated, Life is Too Short"), Yale Alumni Magazine, Circa 1975 October (Box 41, Folder 206)
    - On religion, Oshkosh, Wisconsin, 1976 March 2 (Box 41, Folder 207)
    - "Charles Hartshorne," Metaphysical Society meeting, Vanderbilt University, 1977 March (Box 41, Folder 208)
    - "Fifty Years of It," Metaphysical Society meeting, Vanderbilt University, 1977 March (Box 42, Folder 209)
    - "Replies to Mr. Harris and Mr. Findlay," Metaphysical Society meeting, Vanderbilt University, 1977 March (Box 42, Folder 210)
    - "Reply to Mr. Rorty," Metaphysical Society meeting, Vanderbilt University, 1977 March (Box 42, Folder 211)
    - "Faith and Reason," talk to Directed Studies, Yale University, 1977 April 18 (Box 42, Folder 212)
    - "Professors Emeriti," Yale Alumni Magazine, October circa 1977 (Box 42, Folder 213)
    - "What is the Use of Philosophy?," Vassar College, 1978 April 7 (Box 42, Folder 214)
    - "Einstein's Thought on War and Peace," Einstein Symposium, University of Southern Illinois, 1979 February 28 (Box 42, Folder 215)
    - "Einstein, Quakerism, and Peace," Friends Journal, Circa 1979 May 1 (Box 42, Folder 216)
    - "Memories and Reflections in Honor of Grace de Laguna," Bryn Mawr College, 1979 September 28 (Box 42, Folder 217)
      See also: box 80
    - "Some Oxford Philosophers," American Oxonian, Circa 1979 Fall (Box 42, Folder 218)
    - Boston University Symposium, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 219)
    - "The Rational Outlook," Philosophers on Their Own Works, Circa 1980 May (Box 42, Folder 220)
    - "Reply to Harris" ("Rationalism: A Reply toHarris"), Idealistic Studies, Circa 1980 May (Box 42, Folder 221)
    - "Edmund Taite Silk", 1981 April 15 (Box 42, Folder 222)
    - "The Difficulties of Being Reasonable," New England College, 1981 October 23 (Box 42, Folder 223)
      See also: box 81
    - Saturday Morning Club, 1981 November 7 (Box 42, Folder 224)
    - The Rationalist Outlook," Philosophes critiques d'eux-memes, Circa 1981 (Box 42, Folder 225)
    - "Time," Friends Journal, Circa 1982 January 15 (Box 42, Folder 226)
    - "On the Difficulties of Being Reasonable," Swarthmore College Bulletin, Circa 1982 January (Box 42, Folder 227)
    - "One Man's Humanism," Free Inquiry, Circa 1983 Fall (Box 42, Folder 228)
    - "Bradley: Some Memories and Impressions," Cincinnati meeting of Western Division, Circa 1983-1984 (Box 42, Folder 229)
    - "Think," Boston University Commencement, 1984 May 13 (Box 42, Folder 230)
    - Remarks at Mildred Pierce's 70th birthday (not delivered), 1984 August 4 (Box 42, Folder 231)
    - "Bradley on Relations," The Philosophy of F.H. Bradley, Circa 1984 (Box 42, Folder 232)
    - Foreword to Studies in Personalism, Circa 1984 (Box 42, Folder 233)
    - "T. S. Eliot at Oxford," The Southern Review, Circa 1985 October (Box 42, Folder 234)
    - "The Association Sixty Years Ago," Proceedings and Addresses, American Philosophical Society, Circa 1986 (Box 42, Folder 235)
    - "Mr. Harris on Internal Relations," Dialetic and Contemporary Science: Essays in honor of Errol E. Harris, Circa 1988 (Box 42, Folder 236)
    - "Blessed are the Reasonable", undated (Box 42, Folder 237)
    - On Brooks, R. C., undated (Box 42, Folder 239)
    - "A Conscientious Objector Against Conscientious Objection", undated (Box 42, Folder 240)
    - "Critical Reflections on Karl Barth," Princeton Theological Seminary, undated (Box 42, Folder 241)
    - "Current Issues in Education", undated (Box 42, Folder 242)
    - "Determinism Reconsidered", undated (Box 42, Folder 243)
    - "Education as Philosophy," Annapolis version, undated (Box 42, Folder 244)
    - "Emil Brunner", undated (Box 43, Folder 245)
    - "Ethics and Neutrality", undated (Box 43, Folder 246)
    - "Ethics, Theology, and Foreign Policy", undated (Box 43, Folder 247)
    - "An Examination of Pacifism", undated (Box 43, Folder 248)
    - On Germany and the war, undated (Box 43, Folder 249)
    - "Great English Sentences", undated (Box 43, Folder 250)
    - On Kierkegaard, undated (Box 43, Folder 251)
    - From the Montague volume, undated (Box 43, Folder 252)
    - "Mysticism and Pacifism", undated (Box 43, Folder 253)
    - "The Nature of Honors Study", undated (Box 43, Folder 254)
    - "The Nemesis of Pacifism", undated (Box 43, Folder 255)
    - "The Objectivity of Moral Judgement", undated (Box 43, Folder 256)
    - On peace, radio speech, undated (Box 43, Folder 257)
    - "The Pendulum Swings on Church and State", undated (Box 43, Folder 258)
    - On being a Philosopher, undated (Box 43, Folder 259)
    - "The Physical Basis", undated (Box 43, Folder 260)
    - "The Place of Belief in Religion", undated (Box 43, Folder 261)
    - "The Pope and Dr. Kung", undated (Box 43, Folder 262)
    - "Preamble to the Future", undated (Box 43, Folder 263)
    - "Questions for John Wild", undated (Box 43, Folder 264)
    - On the Rhodes Scholarships, undated (Box 43, Folder 265)
    - "Sigmund Freud", undated (Box 43, Folder 266)
    - "Spinoza", undated (Box 43, Folder 267)
    - "Subjectivism in Ethics - A Criticism", undated (Box 43, Folder 268)
    - "Suggestions for Study", undated (Box 43, Folder 269)
    - "The Teacher", undated (Box 43, Folder 270)
    - "Three Types of Pacifism - Part I: Intuitional Pacifism", undated (Box 43, Folder 271)
    - "Three Types of Pacifism - Part II: Utilitarian Pacifism", undated (Box 43, Folder 272)
    - "Three Types of Pacifism - Part III: Collective Security", undated (Box 43, Folder 273)
    - "To My Critics", undated (Box 43, Folder 274)
    - "Two Types of Pacifism", undated (Box 43, Folder 275)
    - "Understanding", undated (Box 43, Folder 276)
    - To the United States Naval Academy, undated (Box 43, Folder 277)
    - "The Value of Philosophy", undated (Box 43, Folder 278)
    - "Vitality in Scholarship", undated (Box 43, Folder 279)
    - "Welcome to Freshmen", undated (Box 43, Folder 280)
    - Westermarch and Relativity, undated (Box 43, Folder 281)
    - "Why I Like the Friends", undated (Box 43, Folder 282)
    - "Will Vocational Pacifism Serve?", undated (Box 43, Folder 283)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 43, Folder 284-288)
    - Book reviews, 1950s, 1960-1962, 1964-1968, 1970s, 1981, undated (Box 43, Folder 289-293)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1930-1986 (Box 44, Folder 294)
    - Notes for talks, undated (Box 44, Folder 295-301)
    - Wedding remarks, at various locations, 1934-1972 (Box 44, Folder 302)
    - Fragments, undated (Box 44, Folder 303)
  - Manuscripts: books
    - Behaviorism (unpublished), Circa 1964 (Box 44, Folder 304-305)
    - Collected Essays (unpublished): chapters 1-11, [ca. 1940-1987] (Box 44, Folder 306)
    - Collected Essays (unpublished): chapters 12-26, [ca. 1940-1987] (Box 45, Folder 307)
    - Collected Essays (unpublished): chapters 27-34, [ca.1940-1987] (Box 45, Folder 308)
    - Four Reasonable Men: notes, pre-1984 (Box 45, Folder 309)
    - The Nature of Thought: early draft, pre-1939 (Box 45, Folder 310-311)
    - The Nature of Thought: early draft, pre-1939 (Box 46, Folder 312-314)
    - The Nature of Thought: omitted sections, pre-1939 (Box 46, Folder 315-316)
    - The Philosophy of Brand Blanshard: first draft, pre-1980 (Box 46, Folder 317-318)
    - The Philosophy of Brand Blanshard: typescript pp 1-75, pre-1980 (Box 46, Folder 319)
    - The Philosophy of Brand Blanshard: typescript pp 76-150, pre-1980 (Box 46, Folder 320)
    - The Philosophy of Brand Blanshard: typescript pp 151-225, pre-1980 (Box 46, Folder 321)
    - The Philosophy of Brand Blanshard: typescript pp 226-300, pre-1980 (Box 46, Folder 322)
    - The Philosophy of Brand Blanshard: typescript pp 301-366, pre-1980 (Box 46, Folder 323)
    - Reason and Belief: draft of Chap. VI on Kierkegaard, pre-1974 (Box 46, Folder 324)
    - Reason and Belief: draft of Chap. XI, "The Ethics of Belief", pre-1974 (Box 46, Folder 325)
    - Uses of a Liberal Education: notes and drafts, Circa 1972-1973 (Box 46, Folder 326)
  - Published copies
    - [ca. 1914] (Box 47, Folder 327)
    - 1916 (Box 47, Folder 328)
    - 1920 (Box 47, Folder 329)
    - 1925 (Box 47, Folder 330)
    - 1927-1942 (Box 47, Folder 331-346)
    - 1943-1953 (Box 48, Folder 347-357)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 49, Folder 358-359)
    - 1956 Feb-Apr (Box 49, Folder 360)
    - 1956 Jun-Sep (Box 49, Folder 361)
    - 1957-1961 (Box 49, Folder 362-366)
    - 1962-1968 (Box 50, Folder 367-373)
    - 1969-1989 (Box 51, Folder 374-388)
- Teaching Files, 1921-1962; Series III; 2.5 linear feet (6 boxes)
  Material in this series is arranged as either Course notes or Other. The files labeled Other include course syllabi, examinations, reserve reading lists, and class lists. Materials are arranged in folders by course and are listed in alphabetical order by course title.
  - Course notes
    - Classical Problems of Philosophy (Swarthmore College), Circa 1925-1945 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Contemporary Idealism (University of Michigan?): lectures 1-13, [ca. 1921-1925] (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Contemporary Idealism (University of Michigan?): lectures 14-28, [ca. 1921-1925] (Box 52, Folder 3)